<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software Fellowship 2023</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/</link><description>Recent content on Software Fellowship 2023</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sf23.locus.com.np/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Day 1: Introduction to Software Development</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day1/day1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day1/day1/</guid><description>Resource link here Software doesn&amp;rsquo;t wear out There is important distinction between other engineering products and software product, lets take an example of the hardware,As time passes, issues in hardware increase due to lot of reason like friction, radiation and physical damages but it is not the case in software. Software product should evolve with time, due to patches and bugfixes software becomes robust as time passes, this is to say, failure rate decreases.</description></item><item><title>Day 2, 3 and 4: Git, debugging and Python Basics and Intermediate</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day2/day2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day2/day2/</guid><description>Day 4 github link Resource Link here Python Guides What is Python? Python is an interpreted, object-oriented, high-level, dynamically semantic programming language. It is particularly desirable for Rapid Application Development as well as for usage as a scripting or glue language to tie existing components together. Python&amp;rsquo;s straightforward syntax prioritizes readability and makes it simple to learn, which lowers the cost of program maintenance. Python&amp;rsquo;s support for modules and packages promotes the modularity and reuse of code in programs.</description></item><item><title>Day 9: How to get your website out to the world!</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day9/deployment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day9/deployment/</guid><description>Deployment Until now we have created django application and run it on our own machine. We can see our web app running on our browser on localhost:8000. Now its time to dimystify what this localhost:8000 thing is. To understand this we first need to understand three concepts IP addresses, ports and DNS(Domain Name System). Lets go through them one by one
IP Address IP stands for internet protocol. Millions of computers interconnected forms internet this internt connection is the connection formed with wires(optical fibres) and wireless communication.</description></item><item><title>Day 5: (Part 2) Data, Data and More Data!</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day5/data_analytics_project/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day5/data_analytics_project/</guid><description>Collab link for numpy and pandas link Collab link for Data analytics link Welcome to Data Analytics Data analytics is the science of analyzing raw data to make conclusions about that information. Five Step of Data Analytics Importing the required libraries import pandas as pd import json import plotly.express as px from urllib.request import urlopen Download the dataset from sf23-content Day_05 - Data Analytics !wget https://raw.githubusercontent.com/locus-ioe/sf23-content/master/static/Day5/admission.csv Read the admission dataset downloaded before as pandas dataframe admission_df = pd.</description></item><item><title>Miscellaneous: Command line cheatsheet</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/miscellaneous/miscellaneous/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/miscellaneous/miscellaneous/</guid><description>Command line cheatsheet for Day 9 Connect to remote host ssh -i &amp;lt;path-to-key&amp;gt; username@IP
Explanation: -i stands for identity, we have to show our identity before entering into our remote host
username: our remote host will have user created when creating the vm,so wh have as which user we want to enter our remote host.
Copy file from local lost to remote host scp -i &amp;lt;path-to-key&amp;gt; &amp;lt;file-path-to-copy&amp;gt; &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;@IP:&amp;lt;remote-path&amp;gt;
Printing currenting working directiory pwd</description></item><item><title>Day 10: Containarizing our Project</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day10/containers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day10/containers/</guid><description>Containers Introduction If you have been doing web development or programming in general, chances are you’ve already heard of containers or at least Docker. However without having to realize its importance, it doesn’t make sense to use them and understand them.
Imagine if you need to build project with Django version 3.6 for one application. You install the package through godly python tool called pip. pip install django==3.6 But when you need to develop another application with version 4.</description></item><item><title>Day 5: (Part 1) Data, Data and More Data!</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day5/numpy_pandas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day5/numpy_pandas/</guid><description>Numpy Why numpy?? import numpy as np from timeit import timeit def NPFunc(): np.sum(np.power(np.arange(1,2000000), 2)) return None def PyFunc(): sum([x*x for x in range(1,2000000)]) return None print(timeit(NPFunc, number=1)) print(timeit(PyFunc, number=1)) 0.029838398999999072 0.4973828640000022 Numpy operations are a lot faster than built in python operations.
Numpy array declaration and initialization arr1 = np.array([]) # declares an empty array print(arr1) sample_list = [1, 2, 3, 4, 5] arr2 = np.array(sample_list) # initializes a numpy array using python list print(arr2) [] [1 2 3 4 5] Creating 1D and 2D array and initialize with zero #creates 1D array containing zeros np.</description></item><item><title>Day 6: Figma and web basics</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day6/day6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day6/day6/</guid><description>github link here link figma link</description></item><item><title>Day 7: Django Framework</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day7/day7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day7/day7/</guid><description>Updating Soon</description></item><item><title>Day 8: Django Templates</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day8/day8/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sf23.locus.com.np/days/day8/day8/</guid><description>Updating Soon</description></item><item><title>Software Fellowship 2023</title><link>http://sf23.locus.com.np/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://sf23.locus.com.np/about/</guid><description>Software Fellowship is one of the biggest events hosted by one of the biggest national technological festival LOCUS. This year brings even bigger motivations to start our event with a bang. Students of this fellowship can expect to learn Analytical Web App with all its components. We start from the very basic barebones of programming to deploying a full fledged web application and also dive into the world of Data analytics.</description></item></channel></rss>